* Get Started

* Get Help

* Get involved

* News

Foreman Privacy Policy
======================

This document describes the data Foreman collects about you, why it is collected, what is done with it, and your options for how it’s processed.

The Foreman project does not share data with 3rd parties, except for hosting requirements (e.g. GitHub, YouTube) as detailed below, or when required to by law.

Types of data we collect
========================

* Contact details
    * Name
    * Email address
* Data that identifies you
    * IP addresses
    * Browser UserAgent strings
    * Debug archives
    * Answers to survey questions

How and why we use your data
============================

The website
-----------

The Foreman website is a static site which does not track, collect, store information or set cookies. There is no account for the website itself. The webserver (Apache) logs will contain IP addresses, timestamps, and UserAgent strings - these are log-rotated and deleted after 4 weeks.

The webserver logs are used to produce aggregated statistics about the community, such as popularity of different browsers, operating system packages, plugins, etc.

* Legal basis for this data usage: Legitimate interest

### Documentation

[The Foreman documentation](https://docs.theforeman.org/) is static site which does not track, collect, store information or set cookies. There is no account for the documentation itself.

The documentation is hosted on [GitHub Pages](https://pages.github.com/), which [logs the visitor’s IP address for security purposes](https://docs.github.com/en/pages/getting-started-with-github-pages/about-github-pages#data-collection).

Refer to [GitHub’s privacy policy](https://docs.github.com/en/site-policy/privacy-policies/github-general-privacy-statement) for details.

### API Documentation

[The Foreman API documentation](https://apidocs.theforeman.org/) is static site which does not track, collect, store information or set cookies. There is no account for the documentation itself.

The documentation is hosted on [GitHub Pages](https://pages.github.com/), which [logs the visitor’s IP address for security purposes](https://docs.github.com/en/pages/getting-started-with-github-pages/about-github-pages#data-collection).

Refer to [GitHub’s privacy policy](https://docs.github.com/en/site-policy/privacy-policies/github-general-privacy-statement) for details.

### Website videos

The website does embed videos from YouTube, FOSDEM, and Slideshare - see the links below for details:

for details. These videos do not autoplay.

### Website downloads

The downloads from our website are cached by Fastly, a CDN provider. This may also log your IP address - see [Fastly’s privacy policy](https://www.fastly.com/privacy) for details. We don’t currently use this data at all, but we may use it for aggregated statistics in the future.

Codebase
--------

The Foreman community use [GitHub](https://github.com/) to manage the code that comprises the Foreman project. Refer to [GitHub’s privacy policy](https://docs.github.com/en/site-policy/privacy-policies/github-general-privacy-statement) for details on how GitHub handles the data you post there.

Commit messages can contain names and email addresses. You are free to use psuedonymous data for commit messages. We do prefer a working contact mail in case of needing to contact contributors to the codebase, but it is not mandatory.

We also use non-identifiable data from the codebase to provide aggregated statistics such as average time to merge, number of open pull requests, etc.

* Legal basis for this data usage: Legitimate interest, consent

The Foreman community also runs a self-hosted bug tracker using the [Redmine](https://www.redmine.org/) software. When you sign up for a Redmine account, you provide us with an email address and a name.

Externally, we only use this email within Redmine to contact you about bugs you have reported or subscribed to. You have full control over what emails are sent from your Redmine account preferences.

Email addresses can also be linked to GitHub commits (see above) if the emails match, or manually by an admin (on request). This enables Redmine to automatically attribute issue changes to your user, based on the public commit data from the GitHub repositories (e.g. closing it when you fix an issue). This populates your Redmine “activity” page, which is public.

The bug tracker also uses cookies to store your session.

We also use the bug tracker data to provide aggregated statistics such as number of open/closed bugs, average time to close a bug, etc.

* Legal basis for this data usage: Legitimate interest, consent

Communication
-------------

The Foreman project maintains two public Matrix rooms on [matrix.org](https://matrix.org/), refer to [Matrix.org’s privacy policy](https://matrix.org/_matrix/consent) for details on how they handle your data.

The Foreman community uses a self-hosted forum using the [Discourse](https://discourse.org/) software. When signing up for a Discourse account, you provide a name and email address - and in addition we store the IP address of your most recent connection. The email address is only used to send you updates to your forum topics, personal messages from other users, and digest summaries. You have full control over the emails sent from your Discourse account preferences. The forum also uses cookies to store your session.

We also use the IP addresses and _public_ post data to provide aggregated statistics about the forum community, such as posts-per-month, user engagement, etc. We also use the IP addresses to help identify [sock puppeting](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sockpuppet_(Internet)) and spam accounts.

* Legal basis for this data usage: Legitimate interest, consent

Surveys
-------

The Foreman community runs a survey each year. Completing the survey is opt-in, and providing a contact email address in the survey is _optional_. Such addresses are stored until the survey analysis is complete, and then deleted from the raw survey data before publication. The survey data is used to gain understanding of the community, and aggregated statistics based on the survey results are published each year.

* Legal basis for this data usage: Legitimate interest, consent

Foreman debug archives
----------------------

The Foreman project provides a tool called [foreman-debug](https://github.com/theforeman/foreman/blob/develop/script/foreman-debug) which collects logs from your Foreman server and uploads it to a secure location in our infrastructure. Use of this tool is entirely voluntary (it is never run automatically), and the data is used by our developers to assist users in debugging complex problems. The data is not used for any analysis or statistics, is only accessible to a small number of the Foreman developers, and is deleted regularly.

* Legal basis for this data usage: Consent

Your rights regarding your data
===============================

Your choices
------------

### You can choose not to provide us with personal data

Using a VPN, Tor, or other IP / UserAgent masking service will not affect your use of the project website, as it is entirely static. For Redmine & Discourse, we do not mandate use of real names, and using pseudonyms will not affect the services.

### Your accounts on our services

Your Redmine & Discourse accounts contain options to control what emails are sent to you. 3rd party services such as [GitHub](https://github.com/) retain their own policies and privacy options.

Your rights
-----------

Where the EU General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (“GDPR”) applies to the processing of your personal data, especially when you access the website from a country in the European Economic Area (“EEA”), you have the following rights, subject to some limitations, against the Foreman Project:

* The right to access your personal data
* The right to rectify the personal data we hold about you
* The right to erase your personal data
* The right to restrict our use of your personal data
* The right to object to our use of your personal data
* The right to receive your personal data in a usable electronic format and transmit it to a third party (also known as the right of data portability)
* The right to lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority

If you would like to exercise any of these rights, you may do so by contacting the Foreman Project at [contact us](mailto:privacy@community.theforeman.org) or on [Matrix](https://theforeman.org/support.html#Matrix.orglivechat). Please understand, however, the rights enumerated above are not absolute in all cases, especially in regards to the right to erase your data:

* Git commits will not be rewritten
    * contributing to the codebase is opt-in,
    * providing personally identifying information in commit messages is a further opt-in
    * we have a legitimate interest in contacting contributors and showing IP provenance
* Redmine & Discourse data which is _public_ (i.e forum posts, bug comments etc) will be pseudonymised
    * Your account name, handle, and email address will be scrambled, removing your personal data from the site
    * Posts are _not_ removed, as we have a legitimate interest in retaining the history of discussions about our project

Contacting us
=============

If you have any questions about this policy or our use of your data, please feel free to [contact us](mailto:privacy@community.theforeman.org) or on [Matrix](https://theforeman.org/support.html#Matrix.orglivechat).

Changes to this Privacy Statement
=================================

Foreman reserves the right to update this policy from time to time. Material changes will be posted to the [Announcements list](https://community.theforeman.org/c/release-announcements) and posted to the front page of the [website](https://theforeman.org/). This policy was last updated on 10th May 2024.

Foreman 3.12.0 has been released! [Follow the quick start to install it.](https://theforeman.org/manuals/3.12/quickstart_guide.html)

Foreman 3.11.4 has been released! [Follow the quick start to install it.](https://theforeman.org/manuals/3.11/quickstart_guide.html)

View our [Privacy Policy](https://theforeman.org/privacy.html)

This web site is licensed under a [Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en_GB). Source available: [github/theforeman/theforeman.org](https://github.com/theforeman/theforeman.org)

Thanks to [our sponsors](https://theforeman.org/sponsors.html) for hosting this website and our project services.
